<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>El Blog de Rigle</title>
        <link>https://rigle.xyz/blog/</link>
        <description>Recent content on El Blog de Rigle</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>es-es</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rigle.xyz/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Xubuntu 18.04 en el T100TA</title>
        <link>https://rigle.xyz/blog/p/xubuntu-18.04-en-el-t100ta/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 09:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://rigle.xyz/blog/p/xubuntu-18.04-en-el-t100ta/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://rigle.xyz/blog/p/xubuntu-18.04-en-el-t100ta/asus-t100ta.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Xubuntu 18.04 en el T100TA" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tras ver las últimas actualizaciones en los kernels, consultar el &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/communities/117853703024346186936&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;grupo de Google Plus&lt;/a&gt; y la nueva guía que han hecho describiendo el proceso de instalación de una manera sencilla, me he aventurado a volver a tener Linux en el pequeñín. Además, gran parte de los problemas que había (no funcionaban los botones físicos, ni la retroiluminación, ni el micrófono&amp;hellip;) han sido solucionados.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Como ya expliqué en &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://areidz.github.io/blog/linux-on-asus-transformer/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;la entrada&lt;/a&gt; que redacté en inglés hace unos años, lo primero que hice fue una copia de seguridad del disco duro entero con &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.macrium.com/reflectfree&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Macrium Reflect&lt;/a&gt;, ya que solo tiene 64GB como máximo y, por si rompo algo que no debería, prefiero tener la copia entera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La decisión de cambiar a Linux es bastante personal. En Windows 10 todo &lt;strong&gt;funciona perfectamente&lt;/strong&gt; y es un sistema bastante estable para la tablet, mientras que en Xubuntu no funciona la cámara y hay que hacer algún apaño para que funcione el sonido, que no funciona por defecto tras la instalación. En mi caso, estoy muy familiarizado con un entorno Windows, y me gustaría aprender a &lt;strong&gt;manejarme más con la terminal de Linux&lt;/strong&gt; y, en general, adaptarme más al sistema. Además, aunque el precio de la licencia Windows venga incluida en el precio del portátil, me llama mucho la &lt;strong&gt;filosofía del software libre&lt;/strong&gt;, y utilizando Windows no puedo terminar de comprenderla plenamente. Si queréis echarla un ojo, aquí tenéis el enlace: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/philosophy.es.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/philosophy.es.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;instalación&#34;&gt;Instalación&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El proceso lo empecé mal, porque me descargué Ubuntu en vez de Xubuntu, aunque así pude probar también la nueva versión de GNOME y cómo funcionaba en el portátil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Para la instalación entera del sistema, seguí &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1VTzciobFlp7nO2A_M7RNoqYajN8c9AgR/view&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;esta guía&lt;/a&gt;, así que si tenéis alguna duda, os recomiendo consultarla, porque aquí pasaré algunos detalles por alto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manos a la obra: grabé la ISO en un pen drive con &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rufus.ie&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Rufus&lt;/a&gt; y añadí el fichero &lt;code&gt;bootia32.efi&lt;/code&gt; para que pudiese bootear el proceso de instalación. Tras encenderlo, seleccioné las opciones para tener el sistema a mi gusto y creé particiones usando todo el disco (borrando Windows y respetando el UEFI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El primer problema empieza al terminar la instalación, y es el de &lt;strong&gt;instalar el bootloader&lt;/strong&gt;. Para ello, hay que conectar el WiFi como nos indica la guía:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;cp /sys/firmware/efi/efivars/nvram-* /lib/firmware/brcm/brcmfmac43241b4-sdio.txt &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;#useful now&lt;/span&gt;
cp /sys/firmware/efi/efivars/nvram-*  /target/lib/firmware/brcm/brcmfmac43241b4-sdio.txt &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;#useful after reboot&lt;/span&gt;
modprobe -r brcmfmac
modprobe brcmfmac
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Y pasar a instalar el bootloader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;apt update
apt install grub-efi-ia32 &lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;# grub-pc removed is normal behavior&lt;/span&gt;
grub-install --efi-directory /boot/efi
update-grub
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;El segundo problema viene al &lt;strong&gt;intentar tener sonido&lt;/strong&gt;. Para que funcione, tenemos que descargar &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/0B4DiU2o72FbuOXdwRXhfZ3ZmOFE?tid=0B9C1WK1FQhjfcXNrbzN6djQzajg&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;esta carpeta de ficheros&lt;/a&gt;, extraerla y seguir las instrucciones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;sudo rm /var/lib/alsa/asound.state
sudo mkdir /usr/share/alsa/ucm/bytcr-rt5640
sudo cp HiFi bytcr-rt5640.conf /usr/share/alsa/ucm/bytcr-rt5640
sudo alsactl restore
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tras esto, bajamos el volumen y reiniciamos, aunque todavía no tendremos sonido. Nos queda copiar un fichero para sustituir el que se acaba de crear automáticamente.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;sudo cp kernel4.5.xand4.4.x.asound.state /var/lib/alsa/asound.state
sudo alsactl restore
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Con esto, tendríamos que tener el sonido funcionando, pudiendo modificar los parámetros con &lt;em&gt;Pulseaudio&lt;/em&gt; con el comando &lt;code&gt;pavucontrol&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-instalación&#34;&gt;Post instalación&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tras instalar el sistema operativo, en mi caso me gusta mucho mirar cómo puedo terminar de &lt;strong&gt;optimizarlo&lt;/strong&gt; aunque ya funcione decentemente. Si os interesa mirar cómo podéis optimizar Xubuntu o cambiar ciertos valores para hacerlo más cómodo para vosotros, podéis echar un vistazo a esta guía: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/easylinuxtipsproject/first-xubuntu&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://sites.google.com/site/easylinuxtipsproject/first-xubuntu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mi recomendación es que, al menos, decrementéis el uso del &lt;em&gt;swap&lt;/em&gt;, optimicéis Firefox y desactivéis el uso de Java con LibreOffice (y algunas de las opciones que nos cuentan en la guía). No obstante, este tipo de tweaks pueden llevarnos a tener cierta inestabilidad en el sistema, como apunta &lt;em&gt;Gérard Burger&lt;/em&gt; en este post: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/106814689810829884894/posts/MSQZ43hGm5c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://plus.google.com/106814689810829884894/posts/MSQZ43hGm5c&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otros cambios que he hecho ha sido activar la &lt;strong&gt;sincronización vertical&lt;/strong&gt; en XFCE después de cambiar el entorno de escritorio (ver YouTube o Netflix era un poco suplicio sin ello), instalar los &lt;em&gt;Restricted Extras&lt;/em&gt;, activar los repositorios extra, y borrar los restos que quedaban de GNOME. Además, he cambiado el movimiento del ratón, pasando de tener que pulsar dos dedos y deslizar hacia abajo o arriba como es el estándar en muchos de los touchpads, a realizar círculos en él, ya que me parece muchísimo más cómodo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Si os dáis cuenta, esta vez no he instalado ni Dropbox ni Chrome, porque no los estoy usando tanto como lo hacía en la universidad. Además, esta vez he instalado &lt;em&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/em&gt;, porque me he acostumbrado a esta mezcla a caballo entre editor de código e IDE modular, que me permite trabajar con bastante soltura una vez vas cogiendo el truco. Si lo instaláis y queréis ir aprendiendo los accesos rápidos o distintas configuraciones que podéis cambiar, tenéis un buen tutorial &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/Microsoft/vscode-tips-and-tricks&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;en este repositorio de Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;. Por ejemplo, esta entrada la estoy editando completamente con este editor, pudiendo ver la previsualización de &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; con la combinación &lt;code&gt;ctrl+shift+v&lt;/code&gt; (y, es más, con &lt;code&gt;ctrl+k v&lt;/code&gt; se puede tener una previsualización en directo mientras realizamos cambios), y pudiendo gestionar git directamente en él.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alguna cosa que me queda por cambiar, por ejemplo, es el uso de la pantalla táctil, que funciona como un ratón y sería interesante que funcionase como en Windows, bajo mi punto de vista: poder arrastrar los elementos en vez de tener que pinchar en la barra de deslizamiento. Para la navegación web es muchísimo más intuitivo y accesible, y seguro que de alguna manera se puede cambiar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Por ahora, no echo en falta nada de lo que hacía en Windows, así que seguiré al menos unos meses utilizándolo. Si tenéis cualquier duda respecto al proceso, no dudéis en contactarme por email o por Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¡Un saludo!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Linux on my Asus T100TA</title>
        <link>https://rigle.xyz/blog/p/linux-on-my-asus-t100ta/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://rigle.xyz/blog/p/linux-on-my-asus-t100ta/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://rigle.xyz/blog/p/linux-on-my-asus-t100ta/programming.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Linux on my Asus T100TA" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This entry is going to be my &lt;strong&gt;linux diary&lt;/strong&gt;, so I can keep on records the stuff I&amp;rsquo;m doing on the tablet. Well, let&amp;rsquo;s start from the beginning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;windows-hates-me&#34;&gt;Windows hates me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This change started with the new update of Microsoft OS, &lt;strong&gt;Windows 10&lt;/strong&gt;. I wanted to test it on my tablet, an &lt;strong&gt;Asus Transformer T100&lt;/strong&gt; , to see how it was going. Even though I read a lot about its lack of privacy, I was also curious about all the changes like &lt;strong&gt;multi-desktop support&lt;/strong&gt; (which both Linux and Macintosh have since ages) and &lt;strong&gt;Cortana&lt;/strong&gt; , which offered a lot of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.pcworld.com/article/2874400/windows/windows-10-the-10-coolest-features-you-should-check-out-first.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;features&lt;/a&gt; that seemed to be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; I installed it and, as you can imagine, it lasted about 5 days installed. I&amp;rsquo;ve found every new thing a &lt;strong&gt;waste&lt;/strong&gt; of memory and CPU, and I had to reinstall some drivers like the touch-pad, because it wasn&amp;rsquo;t working correctly. Thankfully, Microsoft offered a &lt;strong&gt;downgrade&lt;/strong&gt; to Windows 8.1 if you didn&amp;rsquo;t like Windows 10, so I tried it. Everything went perfect, except for a thing: That new driver which was installed during the time I was trying Windows 10 wasn&amp;rsquo;t downgraded or something like that, and the desktop kept flashing and restarting even if I restarted the OS. That was the moment I gathered strength to &lt;strong&gt;install Ubuntu&lt;/strong&gt; on my tablet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why &lt;strong&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/strong&gt;? Because it&amp;rsquo;s the only &lt;em&gt;Linux&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;well tweaked&lt;/strong&gt; to have almost every single component working. There are some exceptions of parts which aren&amp;rsquo;t working, like the camera, the microphone and the hardware buttons (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General-purpose_input/output&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;GPIO&lt;/a&gt;), but the rest is working in a really stable way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-start-of-the-journey&#34;&gt;The start of the journey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking this into account, I downloaded &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://forum.xda-developers.com/windows-8-rt/win-8-development/live-asus-t100-ta-magic-stick-t3091481&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;Asus T100-TA Magic Stick ISO&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, version 1.5, I booted up &lt;em&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/em&gt; and I &lt;strong&gt;installed it&lt;/strong&gt; with the included tool to do so. I &lt;strong&gt;overwrote&lt;/strong&gt; the complete &lt;strong&gt;internal flash memory&lt;/strong&gt;, included the UEFI partition. I still have a &lt;strong&gt;backup&lt;/strong&gt; in my &lt;strong&gt;external HDD&lt;/strong&gt; just in case I want to recover my system as it was a couple of months ago, so I&amp;rsquo;m not afraid to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First thing I&amp;rsquo;ve done with the new OS is &lt;strong&gt;delete Unity&lt;/strong&gt;. I hate that desktop environment, so I&amp;rsquo;ve installed &lt;strong&gt;XFCE&lt;/strong&gt;. To do so, I&amp;rsquo;ve used a tool called &lt;code&gt;tasksel&lt;/code&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve used the following commands to install it and execute it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell-session&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell-session&#34;&gt;~ $ sudo apt-get install tasksel
~ $ sudo tasksel&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this, I&amp;rsquo;ve checked &lt;code&gt;Xubuntu-desktop&lt;/code&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;ve unchecked &lt;code&gt;Ubuntu-desktop&lt;/code&gt;. You have to &lt;strong&gt;wait a couple of minutes&lt;/strong&gt; in order to download &lt;em&gt;XFCE&lt;/em&gt; and uninstall &lt;em&gt;Unity&lt;/em&gt; and other applications related, and then the OS reboots and you have &lt;strong&gt;Xubuntu&lt;/strong&gt; totally compatible with your tablet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;programs-and-more-programs&#34;&gt;Programs and more programs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the OS and I&amp;rsquo;ve installed some useful programs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell-session&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell-session&#34;&gt;~ $ sudo apt-get update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt-get upgrade
~ $ sudo apt-get install libreoffice gdebi-core synaptic aptitude vlc xubuntu-restricted-extras libavcodec-extra rar wireshark&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I&amp;rsquo;ve installed &lt;strong&gt;Dropbox&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/strong&gt; (I don&amp;rsquo;t really like &lt;em&gt;Chromium&lt;/em&gt; now, because Google has done a great advance in &lt;strong&gt;memory handling&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Chromium&lt;/em&gt; is still a bit slower and bigger than &lt;em&gt;Chrome&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To install &lt;em&gt;Chrome&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell-session&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell-session&#34;&gt;~ $ wget https://dl.google.com/linux/direct/google-chrome-stable_current_i386.deb
~ $ sudo gdebi google-chrome-stable_current_i386.deb&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to install &lt;em&gt;Dropbox,&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve gone to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/install&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;dropbox.com/install&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded the &lt;code&gt;\*.deb&lt;/code&gt; file, and followed the instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s everything I&amp;rsquo;ve made today. I hope the &lt;strong&gt;touchpad support&lt;/strong&gt; becomes &lt;strong&gt;better&lt;/strong&gt; and it gives us multi-touch as Windows does. That&amp;rsquo;s the only thing I miss, the ability to scroll pages with the touchpad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For further information, have a look at our Google+ Group: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/communities/117853703024346186936&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://plus.google.com/communities/117853703024346186936&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;june-2018-update&#34;&gt;(June 2018 Update)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I was really motivated with the change to Linux, I switched it back to Windows after 6 months using Linux for the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My feeling of the performance wasn&amp;rsquo;t the same as using Windows. Even in 2018, we don&amp;rsquo;t have complete support for this tablet, and we have to take some workarounds in order to have everything working. And there are some things that probably won&amp;rsquo;t work easily, like the camera.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t using Linux for anything I couldn&amp;rsquo;t do in Windows and I needed some Windows programs for my University courses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I have a constant feeling that maybe I should give it a try again. Will I do it? How knows, but if I do it, I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you informed here ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>My first experience with Jekyll</title>
        <link>https://rigle.xyz/blog/p/my-first-experience-with-jekyll/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://rigle.xyz/blog/p/my-first-experience-with-jekyll/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://rigle.xyz/blog/p/my-first-experience-with-jekyll/clean-blog.jpg" alt="Featured image of post My first experience with Jekyll" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;After almost seven years using &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.wordpress.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.blogger.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Blogger&lt;/a&gt; as my main blogging services, I have decided to change my mind, make a step forward and install a simple web/blog with a great frontend and without a complex database and their vulnerabilities. Furthermore, I do not like the feeling of Wordpress owning the content of my blog because it is hosted there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a look at the possibilities I decided to try &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Jekyll is a simple web/blog engine written in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ruby-lang.org&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt; using static pages as entries and posts, so&amp;hellip; no more databases!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posts are written in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; style as raw-text and are automatically converted to static pages thought a template you can edit yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-the-blog&#34;&gt;Installing the blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am using Windows as my main Operative System and Debian as my secondary one. Due to this, I decided to install the server on Windows. This installation and configuration was not a trivial step, so I followed the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://jekyll-windows.juthilo.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;official docs&lt;/a&gt; to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only problem I faced was installing &lt;em&gt;WDM&lt;/em&gt;, which was not compiling in my machine. Nevertheless, everything seems to be working perfectly without it, so I am not going to try to fix it for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;folking-the-template&#34;&gt;Folking the template&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After looking for any good template to start the blog, I found &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://startbootstrap.com/template-overviews/clean-blog/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Clean Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, an amazing template by &lt;em&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://startbootstrap.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Start Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I modified it to add support for &lt;em&gt;Disqus&lt;/em&gt; following &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://help.disqus.com/installation/jekyll-installation-instructions&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;this tutorial&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to this I have comments at the bottom of every post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, I have added share buttons following &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://codingtips.kanishkkunal.in/share-buttons-jekyll/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt;. I had to adapt it to my custom template by creating some new css and html files, loading the css file in &lt;em&gt;head.html&lt;/em&gt; and adding the html to the post template. Maybe you could find it interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;useful-links&#34;&gt;Useful links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To finish the post, I want to share some useful links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll/wiki/Sites&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: some examples of websites using *Jekyll.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: main &lt;em&gt;Jekyll&lt;/em&gt; website with install guides and configuration tutorials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://jekyll-windows.juthilo.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jekyll for Windows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: a website explaining how to install &lt;em&gt;Jekyll&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;em&gt;Windows&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/adam-p/markdown-here/wiki/Markdown-Cheatsheet&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Markdown Cheatsheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: useful cheatsheet to write posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://haisum.github.io/2014/11/07/jekyll-pygments-supported-highlighters/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Supported language highlighters in Pygments for Jekyll and GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;july-2018-update&#34;&gt;(July 2018 Update)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recovered some of the entries of my old Jekyll diary and I am posting them here, even though this blog has another template and design. These days I was using Sublime Text as editor, but lately I&amp;rsquo;m liking &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt; a lot and I&amp;rsquo;m editing this whole blog with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>GitHub student pack</title>
        <link>https://rigle.xyz/blog/p/github-student-pack/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://rigle.xyz/blog/p/github-student-pack/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://rigle.xyz/blog/p/github-student-pack/github-student.jpg" alt="Featured image of post GitHub student pack" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Github is undoubtedly one of the largest webpages when it comes to sharing work with the community. Also, Github allows us to work as a team with the Git version control tools and a nice frontend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the best way to promote the use of this kind of tools among the student? I don&amp;rsquo;t know about your answer, but Github thinks that offering a &amp;ldquo;starter pack&amp;rdquo; is one of the best ways: The &lt;strong&gt;GitHub Student Developer Pack&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To join the offer, you have to set up your account and add your college email or registered centre. Once you do it and complete the formulary, you&amp;rsquo;ll receive your pack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-pack&#34;&gt;The pack&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Github Micro Account&lt;/strong&gt;, which allows us to have 5 private repositories in our GitHub account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;*.me domain&lt;/strong&gt; for free for a year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unreal Engine&lt;/strong&gt; for free as long as we are students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous integration with &lt;strong&gt;Travis CI&lt;/strong&gt; as long as we are students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And many more things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are you waiting to give it a try?
&lt;strong&gt;Official page&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://education.github.com/pack&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://education.github.com/pack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;july-2018-update&#34;&gt;(July 2018 Update)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pack has changed a lot since I wrote this entry, and they have added many more interesting things such as Flatiron School to learn Web Development in a bootcamp, or TapLyrics to prepare A/B tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am no longer a student, so I can&amp;rsquo;t have them, but if you are, go check it out!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
